<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>hyderabad on Dipankar&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.desinerd.com/tags/hyderabad/</link>
    <description>Recent content in hyderabad on Dipankar&#39;s blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>Dipankar&#39;s blog</title>
      <url>https://www.desinerd.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.desinerd.com/tags/hyderabad/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Delhi airport : good infrastructure, bad people</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/delhi-airport-good-infrastructure-bad-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/delhi-airport-good-infrastructure-bad-people/</guid>
      <description>On the 15th, I landed at the new IGI terminal from Hyderabad at about 12.10. Hyderabad was a good experience, but most importantly i realized the most striking things about Delhi as soon as I landed.
The Delhi IGI airport is truly international now (at least by the looks of it), swank restaurants, shops and more. The saddest part is that the people have failed to change their attitude. This is reflected in the what happened when i went to the pre-paid taxi booth (manned by the Delhi police)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyderabad : heat relief - #hyderabad</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/hyderabad-heat-relief-hyderabad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/hyderabad-heat-relief-hyderabad/</guid>
      <description>Today, i reached Hyderabad on a one day stay (well, i am out by tomorrow evening). The weather here is so f**king awesome that it had to be documented. For the last one week, I have been trying to locate cities where I can live without getting a heat stroke. Reaching Hyderabad today really made my day, now i have located a city which is not going to become a desert any time soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mosambe for starters</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/mosambe-for-starters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/mosambe-for-starters/</guid>
      <description>Mosambe is a one-stop shop to find the right jobs and the right talent. It is a platform for you to network with your colleagues, gain greater visibility and find new opportunities. For companies- setting up a branded account, posting a job and finding the right talent is simple, easy, effective and hassle free. Mosambe(http://mosambe.com) is the creation of Kaasu info ventures private limited, a small team based out of Hyderabad.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
