<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>earth on Dipankar&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.desinerd.com/tags/earth/</link>
    <description>Recent content in earth on Dipankar&#39;s blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>Dipankar&#39;s blog</title>
      <url>https://www.desinerd.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.desinerd.com/tags/earth/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rumors and more ....</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/rumors-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/rumors-and-more/</guid>
      <description>To be honest, I am a very conspiracy theory kind of a guy. Always believe things after i can validate certain things personally, that invariably leads to me getting too involved (call it the observer effect). But then again there are certain things that are much bigger than me which i believe are absolute frauds, i will state some of the most obvious ones. Humans landing on the moon (yeah right, NASA is struggling now … wonder why they need to design what already works) NGOs are for the greater good (from what i hear they are only for their own good, time we stopped using the tax payers money for them) Net neutrality (impossible, DNS servers still in the USA … the point is lost on me as to how is it fair, internet as we know is still very much controlled by americans) United Nations / World Bank are global organizations (now that is just BS, if we see the UN with its veto powers ….</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>[story] big bird</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/story-big-bird/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/story-big-bird/</guid>
      <description>http://www.cnn.com/2008/WORLD/americas/05/30/brazil.tribes/index.html?iref=topnews
(CNN) – Researchers have produced aerial photos of jungle dwellers who they say are among the few remaining peoples on Earth who have had no contact with the outside world.
A very random story on this picture, njoi
Vellan and Tipsy were sitting, happily looking at Bela their ummm hot wife, well this is one of the few surviving matriarchal societies (isolated from society, now you know why). If you do notice, there is a slight smirk on Bela’s face … thats is where the story starts.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
