<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>delhi on Dipankar&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.desinerd.com/tags/delhi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in delhi on Dipankar&#39;s blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>Dipankar&#39;s blog</title>
      <url>https://www.desinerd.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.desinerd.com/tags/delhi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Why does ebay india suck !</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/why-does-ebay-india-suck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/why-does-ebay-india-suck/</guid>
      <description>This would definitely count as a rant post ! I am a gadget freak and it seems that all the good stuff is only available at an affordable cost [even after USD to INR conversion] on ebay US or UK. No matter how much one says, ebay India or formerly bazee is a whole lota noise, and little auction. Lets do a small study on what I am talking about here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social media primer for politicians</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/social-media-primer-for-politicians/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/social-media-primer-for-politicians/</guid>
      <description>It has been something that has been going on in my head for a significant amount of time and I believe that it is the right time for politicians and famous individuals to take their online reputation management as seriously as the offline one. Here, i will outline a very basic strategy that i believe will equip celebrities and politicians to strengthen their brands. So lets start with some assumptions that will make our lives easier as the post goes on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delhi airport : good infrastructure, bad people</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/delhi-airport-good-infrastructure-bad-people/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/delhi-airport-good-infrastructure-bad-people/</guid>
      <description>On the 15th, I landed at the new IGI terminal from Hyderabad at about 12.10. Hyderabad was a good experience, but most importantly i realized the most striking things about Delhi as soon as I landed.
The Delhi IGI airport is truly international now (at least by the looks of it), swank restaurants, shops and more. The saddest part is that the people have failed to change their attitude. This is reflected in the what happened when i went to the pre-paid taxi booth (manned by the Delhi police)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green peace action : future actions</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/green-peace-action-future-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/green-peace-action-future-actions/</guid>
      <description>Green peace taking on the various challenges we face in our country.
–
Friday, July 17, 2009, 10 am onwards, RBI Why To highlight the fact that irregular monsoons which can make life hell for mankind, acute water, power and agrarian crisis are few of many impacts that climate change can have. What The threat of drought is looming large over Northern India, Delhi has received less rainfall than normal and the city if facing acute water crisis, to highlight the impact of climate change on the City on July 17, Friday around 30 volunteers will queue up outside RBI with buckets filled with water to deposit in the Bank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyderabad : heat relief - #hyderabad</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/hyderabad-heat-relief-hyderabad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/hyderabad-heat-relief-hyderabad/</guid>
      <description>Today, i reached Hyderabad on a one day stay (well, i am out by tomorrow evening). The weather here is so f**king awesome that it had to be documented. For the last one week, I have been trying to locate cities where I can live without getting a heat stroke. Reaching Hyderabad today really made my day, now i have located a city which is not going to become a desert any time soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IIT versus everyone</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/iit-versus-everyone/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/iit-versus-everyone/</guid>
      <description>“Life’s fair if you don’t compare”
The basis of article is the above quote which has no known author. Yesterday, i was sitting with my friends and i was the only IITian sitting there. When these guys started talking about their university life, well I started to realize that the golden years of fun for them were the toughest years for me and my batch. To start this all out, lets go back to the end of 12th and then college life.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
