<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>january on Dipankar&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.desinerd.com/tags/january/</link>
    <description>Recent content in january on Dipankar&#39;s blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>Dipankar&#39;s blog</title>
      <url>https://www.desinerd.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.desinerd.com/tags/january/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Awesome proto.in, jan 2009</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/awesome-proto-in-jan-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/awesome-proto-in-jan-2009/</guid>
      <description>Proto has been taking place for sometime, but Jan 2009 is my first proto.in attendance and it was worth the trip to Bangalore. I went in with some expectations and yes, they were fulfilled. The highlights of the event is given below. Awesome talks - There was one talk by Bob Young(founder of redhat) which was simply awesome. There were others as well which were informative and fun sessions. Great audience - People from all walks of professional life, met a lawyer, a HR guy, a finance guy and so on … with so much variety one can only choose to get bored of such company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be a Shotgun Startup, at Proto.in January Edition</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/be-a-shotgun-startup-at-proto-in-january-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/be-a-shotgun-startup-at-proto-in-january-edition/</guid>
      <description>How many times have you had a cool idea that never saw the light? Or that amazing conversation you had with your best friends which resulted to nothing? It can be that amazing facebook application to solve all the problems of your single friends, or that Iphone game that will rock the world, or an android application, or that robot which will help elderly people remember their pill times. Whatever it is, this is a time to build it and ride the wave with the support of the entire startup community.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
