<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>india on Dipankar&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.desinerd.com/tags/india/</link>
    <description>Recent content in india on Dipankar&#39;s blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>Dipankar&#39;s blog</title>
      <url>https://www.desinerd.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.desinerd.com/tags/india/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The country and you</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/the-country-and-you/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Aug 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/the-country-and-you/</guid>
      <description>I was having this debate how nationalism in India is on the wane, a whole bunch of people talk about how their houses used to have the Indian flag hoisted on independence day/Republic day. Not anymore through. Its not difficult to see why and how the country is changing.
I do hope we understand the point of sticking it out together as a nation, and possibly be one of the greatest ever in this phase of human civilization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peepli live ! and rural India</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/peepli-live-and-rural-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/peepli-live-and-rural-india/</guid>
      <description>One frustrating movie after the other, Bollywood intends to kill me ! The flavor of the season seems to be satires, especially political ones. After watching some mythology based stuff in Rajneeti, one has to deal with this other end of the spectrum. Its all good, and giving valuable exposure to the plight of our fellow citizens, the actual drivers of our still agrarian driven economy. What is disappointing is that it shows what exists, but not how to go about resolving it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why does ebay india suck !</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/why-does-ebay-india-suck/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/why-does-ebay-india-suck/</guid>
      <description>This would definitely count as a rant post ! I am a gadget freak and it seems that all the good stuff is only available at an affordable cost [even after USD to INR conversion] on ebay US or UK. No matter how much one says, ebay India or formerly bazee is a whole lota noise, and little auction. Lets do a small study on what I am talking about here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Road : the movie ! What was it about again ?</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/road-the-movie-what-was-it-about-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/road-the-movie-what-was-it-about-again/</guid>
      <description>Just watched Road the movie at PVR priya ! For one i am a fan of weekday movie watching … Much better the crowd is less and i can hear everything real loud and clear.
It turns out that this movie with all its “starbucks” lines is clearly meant to be an art movie of the US and European audiences. It is highly improbable that a kid in middle of Rajisthan is talking about this particular brand and over it actually moves on that easily from his current dhaba employer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dragflick gods : Abbas and Taekema</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/dragflick-gods-abbas-and-taekema/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Mar 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/dragflick-gods-abbas-and-taekema/</guid>
      <description>Now this Hockey world cup has one convert in me ! I saw what pakistan’s Sohail Abbas can do with his dragflicks … he is god when it comes to that skill. Taekema is as good, in the first Holland match it was fairly obvious why you need quality penalty corner players.
I am surely not like to be the one who defends when either of them is taking a potshot at the net.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clear and present danger</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/clear-and-present-danger/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/clear-and-present-danger/</guid>
      <description>This title is reminiscent of the Harrison Ford movie, but is very applicable to how my country (India) goes about its foreign policy. As a rather naive spectator to the global policy game, here are some conclusions that I have based my current statement on. Being rather country-locked, and especially nations that are in a constant state of political flux. We are in a tremendous disadvantage, unable to appease them or take control of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Social media primer for politicians</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/social-media-primer-for-politicians/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/social-media-primer-for-politicians/</guid>
      <description>It has been something that has been going on in my head for a significant amount of time and I believe that it is the right time for politicians and famous individuals to take their online reputation management as seriously as the offline one. Here, i will outline a very basic strategy that i believe will equip celebrities and politicians to strengthen their brands. So lets start with some assumptions that will make our lives easier as the post goes on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green peace action : future actions</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/green-peace-action-future-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/green-peace-action-future-actions/</guid>
      <description>Green peace taking on the various challenges we face in our country.
–
Friday, July 17, 2009, 10 am onwards, RBI Why To highlight the fact that irregular monsoons which can make life hell for mankind, acute water, power and agrarian crisis are few of many impacts that climate change can have. What The threat of drought is looming large over Northern India, Delhi has received less rainfall than normal and the city if facing acute water crisis, to highlight the impact of climate change on the City on July 17, Friday around 30 volunteers will queue up outside RBI with buckets filled with water to deposit in the Bank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teja drops real bombs (finally)</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/teja-drops-real-bombs-finally/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/teja-drops-real-bombs-finally/</guid>
      <description>Tejas crosses a milestone
Ravi Sharma
BANGALORE: In a milestone, a Light Combat Aircraft (LCA) Tejas took off from here and for the first time dropped live stores (bombs) at a firing range.
The dropping of two 25-pounder bombs, with one striking the target and the other falling within the inner 25 yard circle, was undertaken by Prototype Vehicle-3 of the LCA programme.
The successful dropping of the light, marker bombs will enable the Aeronautical Development Agency (ADA) – designers of the fly-by-wire LCA – to not only prove the working of the aircraft’s flight control software for weapon drops and aiming, but also take forward the LCA’s weaponisation programme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome proto.in, jan 2009</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/awesome-proto-in-jan-2009/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/awesome-proto-in-jan-2009/</guid>
      <description>Proto has been taking place for sometime, but Jan 2009 is my first proto.in attendance and it was worth the trip to Bangalore. I went in with some expectations and yes, they were fulfilled. The highlights of the event is given below. Awesome talks - There was one talk by Bob Young(founder of redhat) which was simply awesome. There were others as well which were informative and fun sessions. Great audience - People from all walks of professional life, met a lawyer, a HR guy, a finance guy and so on … with so much variety one can only choose to get bored of such company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proto.in January&#39;09, Bangalore</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/proto-in-january-09-bangalore/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/proto-in-january-09-bangalore/</guid>
      <description>After its resounding successes in its past four editions, Proto.in is back on 23 &amp;amp; 24 january at bangalore to further strengthen its position as India’s premier start-up event. Proto.in has built a reputation of being the one event the entire entrepreneurial ecosystem looks forward to, across the length and breadth of India. Having witnessed successful past editions in Delhi and Chennai and gearing up for the next one in Bangalore, Ravi Narayanan, a well known entrepreneur and an advisor to proto.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>government aka sarkar</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/government-aka-sarkar/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/government-aka-sarkar/</guid>
      <description>Well, my name is Dipankar Sarkar. And Sarkar is hindi for goverment … so one my friends (specifically Varun Gulshan) would keep calling me that which to be honest is a fantastic nickname ;). Jokes apart, I guess i am a bit frustrated with how things work around me. As an individual who says “chop, chop” as he is in a perennial hurry, it kills me to see how things work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
