<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>interesting on Dipankar&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.desinerd.com/tags/interesting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in interesting on Dipankar&#39;s blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>Dipankar&#39;s blog</title>
      <url>https://www.desinerd.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.desinerd.com/tags/interesting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hyderabad : heat relief - #hyderabad</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/hyderabad-heat-relief-hyderabad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/hyderabad-heat-relief-hyderabad/</guid>
      <description>Today, i reached Hyderabad on a one day stay (well, i am out by tomorrow evening). The weather here is so f**king awesome that it had to be documented. For the last one week, I have been trying to locate cities where I can live without getting a heat stroke. Reaching Hyderabad today really made my day, now i have located a city which is not going to become a desert any time soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Waltz in bugland</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/waltz-in-bugland/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/waltz-in-bugland/</guid>
      <description>I have been working on other people’s bugs for the last couple of weeks and it has been a terribly painful experience. This has been a great experience which has taught me a lot of corrective measures for the roadmap ahead for me. Some basic observations are Not everyone can program or should program - Conceptually it is really easy to type in read a tutorial or 2. But what i saw is pure torture for a guy like me , you need some talent to write a decent application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QOTD : quote of the day</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/qotd-quote-of-the-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/qotd-quote-of-the-day/</guid>
      <description>“What gets measured gets done. What gets measured and fed back gets done well. What gets rewarded gets repeated.”John Earl Jones</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is Pragmatism ?</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/what-is-pragmatism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/what-is-pragmatism/</guid>
      <description>What is Pragmatism ? Something i had little idea about it turns out. Seems i need to read up a lot more about the words i encounter. What stories they hide within their seemingly mundane meanings. The most influential philosophy in America in the first quarter of the twentieth century. Viewed against the widely diversified intellectual currents that have characterized American life, pragmatism stands out as an energetically evolved philosophical movement.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
