<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>july on Dipankar&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.desinerd.com/tags/july/</link>
    <description>Recent content in july on Dipankar&#39;s blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>Dipankar&#39;s blog</title>
      <url>https://www.desinerd.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.desinerd.com/tags/july/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Green peace action : future actions</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/green-peace-action-future-actions/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/green-peace-action-future-actions/</guid>
      <description>Green peace taking on the various challenges we face in our country.
–
Friday, July 17, 2009, 10 am onwards, RBI Why To highlight the fact that irregular monsoons which can make life hell for mankind, acute water, power and agrarian crisis are few of many impacts that climate change can have. What The threat of drought is looming large over Northern India, Delhi has received less rainfall than normal and the city if facing acute water crisis, to highlight the impact of climate change on the City on July 17, Friday around 30 volunteers will queue up outside RBI with buckets filled with water to deposit in the Bank.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyderabad : heat relief - #hyderabad</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/hyderabad-heat-relief-hyderabad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/hyderabad-heat-relief-hyderabad/</guid>
      <description>Today, i reached Hyderabad on a one day stay (well, i am out by tomorrow evening). The weather here is so f**king awesome that it had to be documented. For the last one week, I have been trying to locate cities where I can live without getting a heat stroke. Reaching Hyderabad today really made my day, now i have located a city which is not going to become a desert any time soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nominations for Proto.in Pune, are Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/nominations-for-proto-in-pune-are-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/nominations-for-proto-in-pune-are-open/</guid>
      <description>Amidst much excitement that is bubbling up at the Proto.in camp, we are happy to announce that the nominations for the upcoming edition are now open! The nominations will stay open till June 15th, and that is just a short stint away. Do race to it, and if you are a startup in the Indian landscape and absolutely believe that you have something to share, then this is the platform you’ve been waiting for.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
