<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>mumbai on Dipankar&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.desinerd.com/tags/mumbai/</link>
    <description>Recent content in mumbai on Dipankar&#39;s blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>Dipankar&#39;s blog</title>
      <url>https://www.desinerd.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.desinerd.com/tags/mumbai/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Social media primer for politicians</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/social-media-primer-for-politicians/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/social-media-primer-for-politicians/</guid>
      <description>It has been something that has been going on in my head for a significant amount of time and I believe that it is the right time for politicians and famous individuals to take their online reputation management as seriously as the offline one. Here, i will outline a very basic strategy that i believe will equip celebrities and politicians to strengthen their brands. So lets start with some assumptions that will make our lives easier as the post goes on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Language of politics</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/language-of-politics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/language-of-politics/</guid>
      <description>After the tragic terrorist attacks in Mumbai, we see all the political parties starting their games. Lets have a closer look at what they said and where they went wrong.
Manmohan Singh - A speech which lacked character, though it did not lack the objectivity. In a time of crisis when this was televised what we needed was a stong speech, not this verbal powerpoint. If i had to rate this, it would get a 5 out of 10.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mumbai, terror and NSG</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/mumbai-terror-and-nsg/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/mumbai-terror-and-nsg/</guid>
      <description>Its been a really long 24 hours, I have been following it all on TV or the internet (twitter to be specific). In this process I have see yet another intelligence lapse where probably 200+ people will lose their life on the final count and this will create a dent in our national image. England conveniently goes back home after not even coming close to winning their matches in cricket, a whole host of articles being published about how India will lose its “terror free” south Asia image, and finally how it affects the Delhi elections coming up.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
