<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>new on Dipankar&#39;s blog</title>
    <link>https://www.desinerd.com/tags/new/</link>
    <description>Recent content in new on Dipankar&#39;s blog</description>
    <image>
      <title>Dipankar&#39;s blog</title>
      <url>https://www.desinerd.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.desinerd.com/tags/new/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Playing with corenetworks</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/playing-with-corenetworks/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/playing-with-corenetworks/</guid>
      <description>Just got a new server to play with the corenetworks guys are awesome ! The bandwidth is good, they are bloody straight forward about what works and what does not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyderabad : heat relief - #hyderabad</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/hyderabad-heat-relief-hyderabad/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Jul 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/hyderabad-heat-relief-hyderabad/</guid>
      <description>Today, i reached Hyderabad on a one day stay (well, i am out by tomorrow evening). The weather here is so f**king awesome that it had to be documented. For the last one week, I have been trying to locate cities where I can live without getting a heat stroke. Reaching Hyderabad today really made my day, now i have located a city which is not going to become a desert any time soon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nominations for Proto.in Pune, are Open!</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/nominations-for-proto-in-pune-are-open/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/nominations-for-proto-in-pune-are-open/</guid>
      <description>Amidst much excitement that is bubbling up at the Proto.in camp, we are happy to announce that the nominations for the upcoming edition are now open! The nominations will stay open till June 15th, and that is just a short stint away. Do race to it, and if you are a startup in the Indian landscape and absolutely believe that you have something to share, then this is the platform you’ve been waiting for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>scale or not to scale</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/scale-or-not-to-scale/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/scale-or-not-to-scale/</guid>
      <description>Well, for lack of better topics i will take this opportunity to talk about some cool things that i have started to learn namely the .NET platform. The best part is that i finally get exposed to complete GUI based tools to do nearly everything, (i am sure i will find a way to do most things on the commadline). Well new things and seems i need to scale than the applications i work on ;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kwippy feed for wordpress</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/kwippy-feed-for-wordpress/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/kwippy-feed-for-wordpress/</guid>
      <description>If you notice i now have a RSS feed for kwippy on the sidebar. That is done by using RSS widget functionality within the wordpress theme section. The image below outline the complete setup which i use for my blog.
Its really simple to set this up :).Enjoy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First wordpress plugin : Kwippy poster 1.0</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/first-wordpress-plugin-kwippy-poster-1-0/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/first-wordpress-plugin-kwippy-poster-1-0/</guid>
      <description>Just created my first wordpress plugin, from concept to implementation in 3 hours :D. This plugin basically posts an update on kwippy when you publish a new blog post. This can be a good tutorial for someone trying to build their own plugins actually. Enjoy.
Updated: Official Wordpress plugin page :http://snipper.in/86</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Top 10 events in 2008</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/top-10-events-in-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/top-10-events-in-2008/</guid>
      <description>There were a lot of important events in 2008, which can be defined as good or bad. Here is a list from what i remember of the year gone by. Mumbai attacks - India hardens as a state, we have a new look in our diplomacy. We want action and not reactions from our under-performing politicians. J&amp;amp;K elections - Another great event for our democracy. Finally, a new young CM who can make a difference if he chooses to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web startup strategy in times of recession</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/web-startup-strategy-in-times-of-recession/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jan 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/web-startup-strategy-in-times-of-recession/</guid>
      <description>I think that a lot of people think that its easy to start a web startup and get funding, well part of that is true. Yes, the barrier to start something on the web is extremely low, but lately with the recession getting money for the same is way more difficult than before. So if you are hooked into the web business, here are some simple tips to get through these difficult times.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pownce gone, use kwippy</title>
      <link>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/pownce-gone-use-kwippy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.desinerd.com/posts/pownce-gone-use-kwippy/</guid>
      <description>In a blatant act of self promotion, now that pownce is finished, I can confidently write that we are the only other django based micro-blogging network with some traction. I do admit the user interface needs a bit of work, but if you interact with our community, you will realize that they are a set of amazing people.
So keeping in mind that you want to move on from pownce, try something new … or just try kwippy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
